Finding Aid for Charles E. Lewis papers, 1917-1958 (scattered dates)
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles E. Lewis papers 1917-1958 (scattered dates)
Lewis, Charles E.
0.2 linear ft. and 1 outsize folder
Lawyer in Detroit, Mich., who served as adjutant and judge advocate in the U.S. 339th Infantry during the Allied Intervention in Russia, 1918-1920, the "Polar Bear Expedition." Collection includes biographical and genealogical information, family correspondence, a history of the Manchester, Mich., High School class of 1907; war diary, July-Nov. 1918; correspondence, financial material and memorabilia relating to his war service and veterans' activities; and photographs.
86722 Aa 2 UAl
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Jacqueline Lewis, of Ann Arbor, Michigan, in several accessions beginning in 1981 (Donor no.: 6677 ).
The collection is open for research.
Served as 1st lieutenant, 2d Battalion, 339th Infantry, the Battalion Adjutant. He was later treasurer of the Polar Bear Association.
The papers include biographical and genealogical information, family correspondence, a history of the Manchester, Mich., High School class of 1907, a war diary, July-Nov. 1918, describing his activities in Archangel, two letters, 1931 and 1932, answering questions about various aspects of the Archangel campaign, and Polar Bear Association financial records, 1926-1930. Photographs include group portraits of units of the 339th Infantry, portraits of Lewis in uniform, and photo of Charles E. Lewis (Sr.) in front of his shoe store in Manchester, Mich..
Subjects
Lewis, Charles E.; Soviet Union--History--Allied Intervention, 1918-1920.; World War, 1914-1918.; Polar Bear Expedition.; Veterans--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Polar Bear Association.; Lewis family.; Manchester High School (Manchester, Mich.). Class of 1907.
Genre/Form:
Photographs
- Papers
  - War diary, July-Nov. 1918, and roster (Folder 1)
  - World War I miscellanea and correspondence (Folder 2)
  - Polar Bear Association financial material (Folder 3)
  - Polar Bear Association miscellanea (Folder 4)
  - Biographical and genealogical (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Family (Folder 6)
  - History of Lewis family, 1960s, written by Charles Lewis (Folder 7)
  - Manchester High School class history, 1907, by Charles Lewis (Folder 8)
  - Poetry, by Fannie Lewis1926 (Folder 9)
  - Miscellanea (Folder 10)
- Photographs
  - Photographs, 1840, 1904, 1912, 1918, 1919 (Folder 11)
  - Group photographs (Folder 12)